<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="hrt_keybinding_status_unstable_v1">
  <copywrite>
    Copyright © 2019 Stuart Dilts

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copywrite>

  <description summary="protocol to announce keybinding bindings and status">
    This protocol exposes interfaces to obtain the currently available
    keybindings as well as if a keybinding is currently being entered.

    Warning! The protocol described in this file is experimental and
    backward incompatible changes may be made. Backward compatible changes
    may be added together with the corresponding interface version bump.
    Backward incompatible changes are done by bumping the version number in
    the protocol and interface names and resetting the interface version.
    Once the protocol is to be declared stable, the 'z' prefix and the
    version number in the protocol and interface names are removed and the
    interface version number is reset.
  </description>

  <interface name="zhrt_keybinding_state_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="Announce the current keybinding
                          status">
      This interface announce when the state of the currently pressed
      keybinding changes, as well as when the set of all available
      bindings changes.
    </description>

    <event name="state">
      <description summary="Announce the state of an in-progress
                            keybinding">
        Announce the state of the currently pressed keybinding. The
        value is the pretty-printed state of the bindings, i.e. "C-t g".
      </description>
      <arg name="state" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <event name="bindings_changed">
      <description summary="Announce that the set of available
                            keybindings has been updated">
        Announce the current set of available bindings.
      </description>
      <arg name="bindings" type="string"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
